<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech on Gasimo</title>
    <link>https://gasimo.dev/tags/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech on Gasimo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gasimo.dev/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reality Check, our GameJam submission!</title>
      <link>https://gasimo.dev/blog/realitycheckgamejam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gasimo.dev/blog/realitycheckgamejam/</guid>
      <description>Me and my friends Barbo and Ondrej competed in the 42 hours GDS Gamejam! You can play our submission over at my Itch.io page!&#xD;Whats Reality Check? Its a stylized puzzle-platformer, where you play as a silly wizard being exploring the world with a twist. You possess the ability to rift between alternate versions of reality. One being authentic while the other is a facade of the real world.&#xA;Gameplay Solve puzzles, explore dual worlds, and collect some shiny stars.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech behind Ječná Part 3: Subtitles</title>
      <link>https://gasimo.dev/blog/nightshifttech2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gasimo.dev/blog/nightshifttech2/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone! Welcome to today&amp;rsquo;s devtalk! In this session, we&amp;rsquo;ll be delving into the fascinating realm of subtitles.&#xA;Subtitler The entirety of my subtitle system (conveniently nicknamed &amp;ldquo;Subtitler&amp;rdquo;) is open-source and available over at my github&#xD;!&#xA;During development, I quickly realized that some in-game dialogue may be hard to hear. Implementing a subtitle system was the most obvious solution. However, as the game scaled, it turned out to be a bit more complex than I initially anticipated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech behind Ječná Part 2: Environment</title>
      <link>https://gasimo.dev/blog/nightshifttech3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gasimo.dev/blog/nightshifttech3/</guid>
      <description>Heya everyone! It&amp;rsquo;s time for a healthy dose of tech talk, where I rant about how I developed Nightshift. This time we are looking at the graphics, environment, and optimization efforts in Nightshift (This will not cover ray-tracing as that was more of an experiment than a feature, and is currently not even performant enough to be considered usable).&#xA;Lighting Ječná Nightshift environment is lit by various artificial lights ranging from hallway lamps, monitors, and flashlight down to table lamps.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech behind Ječná Part 1: Interaction System</title>
      <link>https://gasimo.dev/blog/nightshifttech1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gasimo.dev/blog/nightshifttech1/</guid>
      <description>Greetings everyone! Its time for some Gasimo Tech Tips, where I rant about some of the systems I have developed for Nightshift (some are open-sourced over at my github!). This one focuses on the interaction framework.&#xA;Interaction System This is one of the first components I have developed for Nightshift back in the day where it was just a demonstration student project. I wanted to get rid of the commonly used raycast-based system, which plagues the majority of first person indie horror games.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
